<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drafts | Franco Sebastián Benítez</title>
    <link>/drafts/</link>
      <atom:link href="/drafts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Drafts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>es</language><copyright>Franco Sebastián Benítez © 2020 </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Drafts</title>
      <link>/drafts/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crisis de replicabilidad</title>
      <link>/drafts/replicabilidad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/drafts/replicabilidad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;En, 2011 dos hechos claves marcaron un hito dentro de la investigación psicológica: el caso de fraude científico de Stepel, y el estudio de Bem sobre percepción extrasensorial (Renkewitz &amp;amp; Heene, 2019). En el primer caso, Stepel reconoció haber manipulado los datos (Voger, 2011). En el segundo caso, Bem reportó nueve estudios exitosos, aunque subsecuentes estudios fallaron a replicarlo (Schimmack, 2012). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These activities are now commonly known as the open science movement, which regards research transparency as a means against human error, sloppiness, publication bias, and fraud in science.
Although Bem reported nine successful studies, subsequent studies failed to replicate this finding and raised concerns about the integrity of Bem&amp;rsquo;s studies (Schimmack, 2012).
New initiatives that are called open science are likely to improve the replicability of psychological science in the future, although progress towards this goal is painfully slow.
In empirical studies with sampling error, replicability refers to the probability of a study with a significant result to produce a significant result again in an exact replication study of the first study using the same sample size and significance criterion (Schimmack, 2017).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuentes útiles para estudiantes de psicología</title>
      <link>/drafts/fuentes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/drafts/fuentes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;La siguiente lista engloba algunas herramientas para reflexionar críticamente sobre el rol de la psicología a nivel internacional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;podcasts&#34;&gt;Podcasts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En español:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En inglés:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;herramientas-organizacionales&#34;&gt;Herramientas organizacionales&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;r&#34;&gt;R&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cuentas-de-twitter&#34;&gt;Cuentas de Twitter&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
